大杯泡沫无糖香草脱脂拿铁
Grande skim latte, two pumps sugar-free vanilla.
知我者  卡塞尔也
Castle, I think you read my mind.
手术伤口疼吗
Surgery?
对
Yeah.
有时疤会有点紧
Sometimes the scar pulls a bit.
那天的事你还是什么都记不得吗
And you still don't remember anything about that day?
完全记不得
No. It's a blank.
真想不到今秋水泥大衣又回潮了
Who knew cement overcoats would be back for fall?
我得先手动凿开混凝土才能做尸检
I need to chisel out the concrete by hand before I can autopsy,
但她死于枪击  这毫无疑问
but it's pretty clear she was shot to death.
在泥土里找到了两枚子弹
Found these two slugs in the dirt.
貌似是九毫米口径的
Looks to be a 9-millimeter.
凶手很专业
Guy was a pro.
双枪夺命
Double tap.
一枪击中脑后  她倒下
One in the back of the head, she falls,
再开一枪以防万一
then he hits her again to make sure.
再把她埋在沙子里
Buries her in the sand.
只等着水泥车
And then waits for the cement truck
早上来完成毁尸灭迹
to come in in the morning to finish off the job.
处决型凶杀  水泥车
Execution-style murder, cement trucks--
有没有人觉得像是黑帮刺杀
Can anyone else say mob hit?
这里可有"坚实"的证据啊
I'm looking at concrete evidence right here.
包是这里面找到的吗
Is that purse from in here?
对  她的皮尔斯大学学生证上
Yeah. According to her Pearce College I.D.,
写着死者名叫简·赫茨菲尔德
our victim's name is Jane Herzfeld.
大学生
A college student?
倒是不像黑帮会杀的人
That's not a typical mob victim.
我请弹道分析科的人帮忙
Called in a favor to ballistics.
今天应该就能拿到结果了
We should get results today.
你找到她亲属了吗
Did you reach the next of kin?
她妈妈正在赶来
Her mother's on her way in.
简是独生女
Jane was an only child.
那太惨了
That's a hell of a thing.
是啊
Yeah.
她还有个室友
She also had a roommate--
去密歇根探亲了  不过她明天就回来
in Michigan visiting her folks, but she's back tomorrow.
她做了什么事  会被人弃尸阴沟
What was this girl into that got her dumped into a ditch?
目前看来
As far as I can tell,
她做了家教
all she was into was tutoring other students.
她死的当天行程安排的满满的
She was booked solid for the day she died.
奇怪的是那天早晨她取消了所有约会
What's weird is that she canceled her appointments that morning.
她的学生说这不是她的作风
Her students say that it wasn't like her.
她是超级尽责的人
She was super conscientious.
她有给出取消的理由吗
Did she tell them why she was canceling?
她只说有重要的事
All she said was, something important had come up.
或许她知道自己身陷麻烦
Maybe she knew she was in trouble.
死亡时间约在晚十点到午夜间
I'm putting the time of death between 10:00 and 12 midnight.
我还找到了这个
And I found this...
瘀伤
Bruising,
不到一天前造成的
no more than a day old.
他肯定抓住了她  或许是强迫她上车
He must have grabbed her, maybe forced her into a car?
而且  我在她的衬衫上找到了可卡因残留物
Also, I found traces of cocaine residue on her shirt,
但初步毒理检查却毫无发现
but the preliminary tox is clean.
她体内没有毒品也没有酒精
No drugs or alcohol in her system.
或许是凶手带她走到凶杀现场期间
The killer could've transferred it to her shirt
弄到她衬衫上的
when he walked her to the murder site.
看起来
From the looks of it...
她知道自己在劫难逃
she knew she was gonna die.
她拳头里紧握着这个
I found this clutched in her fist.
他让她祈祷  然后杀了她
He let her say a prayer before he shot her.
这可不够专业啊
That's not very professional.
不
No.
看来简认识凶手
More like Jane knew her killer.
昨晚她没打电话来
When I didn't hear from her last night,
我就知道出事了
I knew something was wrong.
我们每晚都会通话的
We always talked at the end of the day.
赫茨菲尔德太太  简为了赚外快做家教
Mrs. Herzfeld, Jane was tutoring people to make extra cash.
你知道她昨天为什么取消了全部约会吗
Do you know why she canceled all of her appointments yesterday?
有没有可能  简除了家教还做了别的什么
Is it possible that Jane was doing something other than tutoring,
可能让她卷入麻烦的事
something that might have gotten her into trouble?
什么样的事
Something like what?
我们在她体内没有发现毒品
Look, we didn't find any drugs in Jane's system,
但法医在她衣服上找到了一些可卡因
but the M.E. did find traces of cocaine on her clothes.
简绝不会跟毒品弄到一块
Jane would never be involved with drugs!
没错  但她可能跟与毒品有关的人弄到一块了
Yeah, but she might have been involved with people who were.
我们认为她认识凶手
And we think that she knew her killer.
她有个男友我不喜欢
There was a boyfriend I didn't like.
他们五个月前分手了
They broke up five months ago.
你为什么不喜欢他
And what did you not like about him?
他不直视我的眼睛
He wouldn't meet my eye.
他们吵架
They would fight.
我看到她身上有瘀伤
I saw bruises on her.
你记得他的名字吗
Do you remember his name?
芬巴尔·乔瑟夫·麦奎恩
Finbar Joseph McQueen,
也叫芬恩
A.K.A. Finn.
因携带可卡因并有意贩卖入狱两年
Did a deuce on cocaine charges, possession with intent.
这就能解释蕾妮在尸体上找到的残留物了
Well, that could explain the residue Lanie found on her body.
破门侵入  袭击他人
B&E, simple assault...
没有跟枪有关的犯罪
There's nothing gun related.
或许他决心更上一层楼
Maybe he decided to step up the game.
查到他的住址了吗
Do we have a location on this guy?
查到了  这才是最好的部分呢
Yeah, that's the best part.
我们跟麦奎恩的假释官谈过
Talked to McQueen's parole officer.
他说麦奎恩在西98街645号干活
He says that McQueen is doing a job at 645 W. 98th street.
做建筑工人
Construction.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
真不敢相信她死了
I can't believe she's dead.
你最后一次见到简是什么时候
When is the last time you saw Jane?
几周前
A couple weeks ago.
但你们四月份就分手了
But you--you broke up in April,
这么说  你们还有联系吗
so... you stayed in touch?
我们是朋友  对啊  我
Uh, I-I was her friend, yeah. I...
我时不时会帮帮她  我
I-I help her out every now and then. I, uh...
借过她钱  她也还了
L-lent her money once, she paid me back.
就诸如此类的
You know, like-- like that.
简缺钱吗
Did Jane have money problems?
作为她的朋友
And as a friend...
或许你跟她说你可以帮她找点事做
did you maybe tell her that you could hook her up,
结果让她陷入自己应付不来的事情中
got her involved in something she couldn't handle?
简绝不会做任何违法的事情...
Jane wouldn't ever do anything that wasn't legit...
-贝克特  -如果你是想暗示这个的话
- Beckett. - if that's what you're implying.
简是个好女孩
Jane was a good girl.
什么
What?
所以我们才分手了
That's why it ended with her.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
她希望我能金盆洗手
She wanted me to go straight.
绝对不会弄错吗
And there's no chance that's a mistake?
我就是做不到
I just couldn't.
我不断跟她说
I kept telling her...
我就是这样的
This is who I am.
别动
Don't move.
那个叫芬恩的家伙
My man Finn,
马上就要招供了
inches from confessing.
怎么了
What?
发生了什么事
What's going on?
弹道分析刚刚出来了
Ballistics just came in.
杀死简·赫茨菲尔德的子弹是
The bullet that killed Jane Herzfeld
发自一把我们已有记录的枪支
is from a gun that's in our system.
格洛克17型
It's a Glock 17.
好消息呀
That's good news.
莱恩  与你以前的配枪匹配
Ryan, it's a match to your old service weapon.
一定出错了吧
That can't be right.
没有出错
It's not a mistake.
杀死简·赫茨菲尔德的枪
The weapon that killed Jane Herzfeld...
是你的那把
it's yours.
她死时手里紧握着十字架
She was holding a cross in her hand when she died.
她祈祷着怜悯
She was praying for mercy.
然后
And then...
她就听到凶手扣下了
She heard him pull the trigger...
我的枪的扳机
of my gun.
去年  我们曾调查3XK连环杀人案
We were working the 3XK serial murders last year.
拘捕了一名嫌疑犯  并且他供认罪行
We had a suspect in custody who had given us a full confession,
于是  卡塞尔和我去了汽车旅馆
at which time, Castle and I went to the motel--
卡塞尔也跟你一起
Castle was with you?
是的  局里把杰端·泰森扣押在
Yeah, the NYPD sequestered Jerry Tyson
一个汽车旅馆里作为目击证人
at a motel as a witness,
卡塞尔和莱恩过去告诉他安全了
and Castle and Ryan went over there to give him the all clear.
而此时你们意识到泰森才是真正的3XK
At which time you realized that Tyson actually was 3XK?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
泰森先发制人
Tyson got the drop on us
把我的警徽和配枪都带走了
and left with my gun and badge.
内务处已经证实那不是莱恩警探的错
Look, detective Ryan was cleared of all wrongdoing by the I.A.B.
我不在乎是谁犯了错
I don't care whose fault it is.
我只在乎把损害降到最低
All I care about is mitigating the damage,
就是说我们得把杰端·泰森这禽兽尽快找出来
which means we track down Jerry Tyson like the animal he is
然后丢回监狱
and we haul him into custody.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
你还好吗
You okay?
杰端·泰森被抓的时候我就好了
I will be when Jerry Tyson's in cuffs.
贝克特
Beckett,
麦奎恩的不在场证明已经证实
McQueen's alibi checks out.
服务员说他在东区的安吉莉餐馆
Waitress confirms he was at Angeli's Diner
一直待到关门
on the east side until closing.
好吧  放了他
All right. Cut him loose.
你知道吗  莱恩
You know, Ryan,
如果泰森就是凶手
if Tyson is the shooter,
那就解释了简被杀的原因
that explains Jane.
并没有直接动机  只是符合他的喜好
No direct motive, just fits his profile--
妙龄金发女郎
She's young, she's blonde.
没错  但3XK案子其它的死者都是被勒死
Yeah, but 3XK strangled those other women.
为什么现在他用起枪来了
Why would he use a gun now?
他说过他喜欢改变作案手法
He told me he likes to change up his MO.
是啊  一定是在我昏倒在地的时候说的
Yeah. He must have mentioned that when I was out cold on the floor.
莱恩  这根本不是你的错
You know, Ryan, none of this is your fault.
他用了你的配枪这件事...
The fact that he used your gun--
那把枪是由纽约市配发给我的
That weapon was issued to me by the city of New York.
我把它弄丢了  现在还有人用它杀了这女孩
I let it out of my hand, and now a girl is dead.
请别再说这不是我的错了
So please do not tell me that it's not my fault.
我去排查简的公寓
I'm gonna start a canvass at Jane's apartment,
让他们把泰森的照片给附近的人看看
have 'em show Tyson's photo around,
弄清楚简的室友什么时候回来
find out when Jane's roommate's back in town.
好的
Okay.
这是警察的心结  卡塞尔
It's a cop thing, Castle.
不  不  我明白的
No. No, I get it.
鉴证组从简的一卡通和
Yo. C.S.U. pulled information
自动提款机记录里查到信息
off Jane's metro card and ATM records.
昨天她在中央车站花了几乎所有的钱
She spent most of yesterday at Grand Central Station.
是的  在四小时内
Yeah, over a 4-hour period,
她在车站里和附近的三台自动提款机上
she made... multiple withdrawals out of three ATMs
进行了多次提款
in and around the train station--
总共八百美元
$800 worth.
她告假一天
So she canceled a day of work
就为了在车站闲晃然后挥霍掉所有存款吗
to hang out at a train station and empty her bank account?
这就是她所谓的重要事件吗
That was the important thing that came up?
我已经在第一时间派了一个小队过去
I'll send a team over there first thing.
让他们去和那里的商贩谈谈
Have 'em talk to vendors,
看是否有人记得见过她
see if anybody remembers seeing her.
或泰森
Or Tyson.
他在杀人前总是先跟踪她们
He stalked his victims before he killed them.
感觉就好像我为了今天的到来
It's like I've been holding my breath for a year,
屏息以待了整整一年
waiting for this day to come.
整整一年我苦思冥想
A whole year of wondering about him,
切齿痛恨
hating him,
魂牵梦萦
dreaming about him,
试着以他的角度思考
trying to think like him...
但还是不知道如何能将他缉拿归案
but still having no clue how to catch him.
缉拿连环杀手不是你的工作
It's not your job to catch a serial killer.
因为我不是警察
Because I'm not a cop.
我总喜欢假装自己是贝克特的拍档
I like to pretend I'm Beckett's partner
就像我是警察一样
and like I'm one of them,
但到像今天这样的时候  我才意识到...
But days like today, I realize, I...
我只不过是在优孟衣冠罢了
that I've just been playacting.
我记得你这"优孟衣冠"可曾拯救过纽约市呢
Your playacting once helped saved New York city as I recall.
去支持你的朋友
Be there for your friends.
站在他们身边  一起努力
Stand beside them, work together.
那就是最大的帮助
That's plenty useful.
相信我
Trust me.
很抱歉  我不认识他
I'm sorry. I don't know him.
简和我只做了六个月室友而已
Jane and I were only roommates for six months.
也许他就是她的男朋友
Maybe he was the guy she was seeing.
简有男朋友吗
Jane had a boyfriend?
她不愿意跟我说他的事
She wouldn't tell me about him,
也不让他来我们这
and... she wouldn't let him come around.
为什么简不愿意谈及他
Why wouldn't Jane talk about him?
她说在关系公开以前
She said that he had some things he needed to figure out
他还有一些事情要处理
before they could go public.
老实说  我想他大概是已婚人士吧
Honestly, I just thought, maybe he was married.
然后  大约在六周之前
Then, like, six weeks ago...
事情出现了变化
things changed.
怎么变化了
Changed how?
她变得总是哭哭啼啼
She was crying all the time
还常常在深夜接到电话
and she would get phone calls really late at night
接了电话后会十分难过
and be really upset afterwards.
你记得任何简接到电话的
Do you remember a specific time or day
确切时间或日期吗
when Jane got one of these calls?
上周四
Last Thursday.
大约十一点
A-around 11:00.
周四晚间十一点  简的手机接到一通来电
Thursday night at 11:04, Jane got a call on her cell.
我们的人说那通电话是从城里山姆酒吧的
Our guys say that call originated on a pay phone
公用电话打来的
in Sammy's Bar in midtown.
过去六周里这个号码每周两通电话
Two calls a week to the same number over the last six weeks?
是他
It's him.
我见过她几次
I've seen her, couple of times.
是和赛斯一起来的
Yeah, came in with Seth.
这是赛斯吗
Is this Seth?
不  那不是他
Nah. That ain't him.
你确定  看仔细了
You sure? Take a good look this time.
赛斯是个熟客
Seth's a regular.
那不是他
That ain't him.
但你们如果想跟赛斯谈谈  留下
But if you want to talk to Seth, just stick around.
他几乎每天都来这
He usually comes in here pretty much every day.
干什么
Doing what?
他常常使用那边那台电话
He uses that phone over there a lot.
和一些獐头鼠目的人们见面
Meets with shifty looking individuals
他说  是一起工作的人
he calls, uh, associates.
有一次  他的夹克卷在背上
One time, his jacket rolled up in the back.
他带着枪
He was strapped.
听起来是个毒贩
Sounds like a drug dealer.
赛斯一般什么时候过来
All right, so what time does Seth usually come in?
大概三点
About three.
你们可以在这等着
Stay if you want,
但我还有事情要做
but I gotta get back to work.
莱恩还好吗
So how's Ryan holding up?
我最后一次伊拉克服役归来  三天后
Three days after my last tour in Iraq,
我跟朋友们在吃饭
I'm at a diner with friends.
一辆车回火
A car backfires.
朋友回头一看  我已经躲在桌底下了
My friends look around. I'm under the table.
莱恩是在等下一起案件
Ryan's just waiting for the next hit.
我不明白的是
Here's what I don't get--
我的枪怎么跑到毒贩手里的
what's a drug dealer doing with my gun?
也许泰森把枪卖了  或扔了
Well, maybe Tyson sold it to him or tossed it,
落到了赛斯手上
and Seth found it.
这不像杰瑞·泰森的做法
That doesn't sound like Jerry Tyson.
3XK做事很有计划
3XK always has a plan.
也许赛斯是个替死鬼
So maybe Seth is a patsy.
今天怎么样  小乔
How you feeling, JoJo?
赛斯  你怎么样
Hey, Seth, how's going?
你可以等下亲自问问了
Looks like you'll be able to ask him yourself.
赛斯  我是贝克特探长  纽约警局
Hey, Seth. Detective Beckett, NYPD.
兄弟们  他逃跑了  他逃了
Back alley. He's on the move! On the move!
站住  我们是警察
Stop! Police!
纽约警局
NYPD!
靠着车站好  快
Get up against the car, right now!
有枪
Gun.
是格洛克17型
It's a Glock 17.
你有持枪许可吗
You got a permit for this?
当然  蠢货  我是警察
Sure do, ponch. I'm a cop.
赛斯·卡沃警探  缉毒组的
Detective Seth Carver. Narcotics.
帮个忙  在我的身份彻底曝光前
Do me a favor and put me in the vehicle
把我押上车  成不
before you blow my cover completely, will you?
让我猜猜
So let me guess.
你们找过她的妈妈和朋友
You talked to her Mom and her girlfriends,
都说简是个天使般的乖乖女  对吗
and all of 'em said that Jane was an angel. Am I right?
你的意思是  她不是
So you're saying, she wasn't?
我遇见她时
I'm saying that when I met her,
是因为她闯红灯  将她拦下
I was pulling her over for blowin' a red light,
在车里的储物箱内发现了毒品
and she had 2 grams in the glove compartment.
简不吸毒
Jane didn't do drugs.
我能说啥
What can I tell ya?
小姑娘车上有毒品
Little miss was riding dirty.
但你没有起诉她
You--you didn't charge her.
系统里没有记录
There's--there's nothing in the system.
是的
Right.
因为当我问她可卡因是哪里来的
That's because when I asked her where the coke came from,
她说是本·李给她的
she told me Ben Lee gave it to her.
-本·李是谁  -本是谁...
- Who's Ben Lee? - Who's Ben...
克利福德·李的儿子
Son of Clifford Lee.
他是汉义堂的老大
He's the head of the Han Yi Tong.
以莫特街上那家中式小吃店做门面
Operates out of a dim sum house on Mott Street.
汉义堂是什么
What's the Han Yi Tong?
堂是一种中式商业组织
Tongs are a Chinese merchant organization.
多数是合法的
Most of them are legit,
但有些是掩护中国黑帮的门面
but some of them are a front for the Chinese mob.
那克利福德·李就像是教父了
So Clifford Lee would be like the Godfather.
是的
Oh, yeah.
克利福德·李的儿子不过卖了她一点毒品
How's Jane supposed to help you get to Clifford Lee
就凭这点  简怎么帮你抓他
based on one coke buy off his kid?
在教育问题上
When it comes to education,
克利福德·李持传统的中国思想
Clifford Lee is an old-school Chinese.
他的儿子们虽说是毒贩
His sons may be drug-dealing criminals,
但也要大学毕业才行
but they still need to graduate college.
本·李是她的一个学生
Ben Lee was one of her students.
她是他的家教
She was tutoring him.
她一周会去他们家两次
Twice a week, she was in their house.
我说如果她能弄到李家犯罪的确凿证据
I told her I would drop the possession charges,
我就不会以持有毒品罪起诉她
if she brought me some solid intel on Lee's criminal operations.
她接受了
She said okay.
但她好像露出马脚  他们就把她杀了
And somehow she tipped 'em off, and they killed her.
就这些
That's it?
我已经给了你一条有用的线索
I just handed you a solid lead.
怎么还想要其他的吗
What, he wants more? What is this?
你说真话怎么样
Yeah, how about the truth?
莱恩  别冲动  稳住阵脚
Come on, Ryan. Keep it together.
你指望我们相信  困扰了你多年的案子
You expect us to believe that you worked a case for years,
然后在一个幸运的周六晚上
and then one lucky Saturday night,
就这么碰巧逮到了个完美的线人
you just happen to roll up on the perfect C.I.?
我也在缉毒组待过  卡沃
See, I did my time in narcotics, Carver.
看得出谁在玩阴招
I know a shortcut when I hear one.
莱恩
Ah, gee, Ryan.
幸好我知道你不会
If I didn't know any better,
要不真以为你是在说我有不当行为呢
I would think you were accusing me of something untoward.
你主动找上简·赫茨菲尔德
You targeted Jane Herzfeld.
你在她的车里放了毒品
You planted those drugs in her car,
然后你强迫她帮你
and then you made her help you out.
你让她一人身入险境
You--you sent her in there alone--
没有后援  没人保护  现在她死了
no backup, no protection-- and now she's dead.
又不是我杀的她
Yeah, well, I didn't make her dead.
一通鬼话
The hell you didn't.
你也许没有扣扳机
You may have not pulled the trigger,
但你跟凶手一样  罪大恶极
but you're as guilty as the creep who did.
那你呢  老兄
What about you, man?
看看你自己
Look at yourself.
传言都说  凶手用的可是你的枪
Word around the house is that that creep used your gun.
自己的枪都弄丢  这警察当的真窝囊
What kind of cop can't keep hold of his own weapon?
你刚才说什么
What did you say to me?
-我们走  -你给我再说一遍
- Let's go. - Say it to me! Say it!
说啊  有种你再说一遍
Say it! I want you to say it! Say it to my--
放手
Hey, break it up.
Break it up.
我们都是警察
We're all cops here. Okay?
如果话问完了
If you're all done,
我就走了
I think I'll take my leave now.
走吧  谢谢你的帮助  卡沃
Yeah. Thanks for your help, Carver.
不客气
You got it.
你这是干什么
What are you trying to do?
想把警监也招过来吗
You want the captain to come in here?
冷静一下
Go cool off.
他就是个混蛋
Guy's a jerk.
我刚到缉毒组时
When I started in narcotics,
真是一无所知
I was so green.
一点都不懂规矩
I-I didn't know how things got done.
一天  我们有大规模缉毒行动
One day, there's this major bust--
抓捕一伙制造冰毒的街党
a street gang cooking meth.
他们把人集中在大堂
They're stacking up guys in the bullpen,
一个一个的做笔录
taking their statements one by one.
乱成一团
Place is a zoo.
我是负责接电话的
I'm answering phones in the squad.
一个女孩打来
Girl on the line,
叫艾丽莎  找我们警督
name of Alisha, asking for my Lieutenant.
我就朝着大堂另一面喊
So I call out across the bullpen,
卢  你的电话  艾丽莎找
"Hey, Lou, Alisha's on the phone for you."
正是她的消息  让我们抓到了人
It was her tip that got these guys nailed,
而所有人都听着我喊出她的名字
and all of 'em just heard me call out her name.
我们整日整夜地找她
Searched all day and all night,
希望赶在她是缉毒警察的消息
looking for her, before the gang could
传出去前  能把她找到
get word back to the street that she was a narc.
那你们找到她了吗
Did you find her?
找到了
I did.
让她加入证人保护计划  但...
Got her into witness protection, but...
那是我做警察干的最蠢的一件事
That was the stupidest thing I'd ever done as a cop...
直到那天  杰瑞·泰森先发制人
Until the day Jerry Tyson got the drop on me
偷了我的枪
and stole my weapon.
卡沃是个混蛋
Carver is a jerk...
但他说的对
But he's got a point.
来吧
Come on.
你知道卡沃哪一点可能说的对吗
You know what Carver could have a point about?
是本·李
Is Ben Lee.
如果本真向简走漏了消息
If Ben did tip to Jane,
那他便有很强的杀人动机
then that's a strong motive.
你想去唐人街转转吗
You up for a trip to Chinatown?
必须的
Hell, yeah.
巡警在中央车站那里找到了线索
Uniforms at Grand Central caught a break.
他们找到了一个在街角邮箱中心上班的职员
They found a clerk who works at a mailbox center around the corner,
那人说简死亡当天曾向他租了一个邮箱
who says he rented a box to Jane on the day she died.
我要去查证一下  你一起来吗
I'm gonna go check it out. You want to roll with me?
不了  我跟贝克特一起
No, I'm with Beckett.
卡塞尔  你要去吗
Castle, you want to come?
我刚刚在想
I-I was just thinking...
如果凶手是李的手下
if our killer is someone in Lee's organization,
那他一定是从杰瑞·泰森那得到你的枪
then he must have gotten your gun from Jerry Tyson.
也就是说凶手可能知道泰森的下落
Which means our killer may know Tyson's whereabouts.
我们抓到了他  就相当于抓到了3XK
We nail him, we nail 3XK.
没错  但泰森的背景跟
Yeah, but there's nothing in Tyson's background
这个中国黑帮一点关联都没有
that indicates a connection to the Chinese Mob.
也许凶手跟李家有关系
Maybe the shooter is connected to the Lees--
在泰森的四年牢狱之灾中
someone Tyson's crossed paths with
跟凶手有过交集
during his four years in prison,
而那人正是为堂做事
someone working for the Tong.
如果我能找到那个人  也许就能找到凶手
If I find out who that someone is, maybe we have our shooter.
要查阅四年的监狱记录
Wading through four years of prison records--
还真是个大工程
it's a lot of work.
我不介意
I don't mind.
那好  我们走
All right. Let's go.
警探们
Detectives.
我猜你们是为简的事而来
I assume you're here about Jane.
请坐
Please, sit.
我知道简曾经是你的员工
I understand Jane was an employee of yours.
对吗
Is that correct?
她曾是我儿子本的家教  这就是本
She tutored my son Ben. Oh, this is Ben,
我其他几个儿子菲利普  大卫  史蒂文
my other sons, Philip, David, Steven.
本  你最后一次见简是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Jane, Ben?
上周
Last week.
前天我们本来约好了
We had an appointment the day before yesterday,
但她取消了
but she canceled.
你们都在什么地方见面
And where would you meet?
有时在学校  有时在我家
Sometimes at school. Sometimes at my house.
简是个好老师吗  你喜欢她吗  本
Was Jane a good tutor? Did you like her, Ben?
她还不错
She was okay.
问这些是什么意思
What's with all these questions?
他刚刚才说没见过她
He just said he hadn't seen her.
菲利普
Philip.
李先生  事实上
The truth is, Mr. Lee,
我们发现了一些有关简的信息
we've uncovered some information about Jane
而干你这行的人可能会为之困扰
that a man in your line of work might find troubling.
你是说她生前做过线人
You mean that she was an informant?
简在大约一个月前跟我交代过
Jane told me herself, about a month ago.
她说有一个坏警察
She said that a bad cop
陷害了她
had framed her
还强迫她协助他
and is forcing her to help him.
我告诉她关于我们她也确实没什么可说的
I told her that there was nothing to tell this man about us
因为我们都是正经商人
because we are honest businessmen.
我希望那位警官等得厌烦了
I hoped the officer would grow tired of waiting
就会放过她
and leave her alone,
但很不幸  事与愿违
but unfortunately, that did not happen.
恐怕你们要找的真凶
I'm afraid your killer
或许远在天边近在眼前
may be closer to home than you think.
卡沃探员已经洗清嫌疑了
We've already ruled out Detective Carver.
当然
Of course.
那你们这些
And what were you...
正经商人在简遇害当晚十点至午夜间
honest businessmen doing between 10:00 p.m. and midnight
都在做什么呢
on the night Jane was killed?
当时我们在家里看电视
We were home, watching television.
如果你们想证实这个消息的话
Please feel free to speak to any of my household staff
可以随便盘问我家的佣人
if you wish to verify this information.
我们一定会的
We will.
爸爸  那些都是什么东西
Hey, dad. What's all that?
囚犯记录
Convict reports.
我要查出杰瑞·泰森
I'm trying to figure out whom the bad guy
把莱恩的枪给哪个大坏蛋了
Jerry Tyson gave Ryan's gun to.
查到了吗
Any luck?
相当于大海捞针
I'm looking for the proverbial needle in a haystack.
那箱子里一定有跟泰森有关的东西
Somewhere in that box is a link to Tyson.
只是我还没有找到
I'm just not seeing it.
我虽然想帮你
Well, I'd offer to help,
但还有一大堆投诉信等着我看呢
but I've got all these complaint letters to read.
怎么  你这是辍学了
What, did you drop out of school
-在消协找了个活儿吗  -才不是呢
- and get a job in consumer relations? - No.
毕业班选我做了
The senior class made me
向行政机构提出倡导的执行联络人
their executive liaison advocate to the administration.
听起来是一项殊荣啊
Well, that sounds like quite an honor.
不算是
Not really.
常春藤大学更喜欢
Ivy League schools look fondly on applicants
当过学生会干部的申请人
who serve in student government,
阿丽克西斯是在再次申请斯坦福之前
and Alexis is beefing up her resume
丰富她的简历
before she reapplies to Stanford.
哪里都一样  如果我还打算上大学的话
Or anywhere, if I even go to college at all.
切尔西已经做了三年的倡导人
Chelsea's been our advocate for the last three years,
当我跟她说我想多尽点力的时候
and when I told her I wanted to be more involved,
她就主动卸任
she offered to step aside
让我接管了这个工作
and let me take over the position.
那她人不错啊
Well, that was nice of her.
不算是
Not really.
-又"不算是"  -是啊
- Again with the not really. - Yeah.
我刚接这活的时候也不知道
I didn't know when I agreed to do it,
你只能数个小时坐在那一动也不动
but you just sit there for hours and hours
听所有人抱怨投诉
and listen to everyone complain.
我想切尔西是厌倦了这份工作
I-I think Chelsea just got tired of it,
盘算着让我接管这烦人的差事
of figured she could stick me with the job.
我还把她当做朋友呢  但我想
And I thought she was my friend, but I guess--
不算是
Not really.
认了吧  孩子
Face it, kiddo.
切尔西给你下了套
Chelsea set you up.
她给你下了套
She set you up.
你的朋友给你下了套
Your friend set you up.
李家的所有佣人都众口一词
The Lees' entire household staff
证实了简·赫茨菲尔德被害当晚
confirms that the family was at home
全家人都在家看电视
watching television the night  was killed.
是啊  意料之中的事
Yeah, well, there's no surprise there.
中央车站那边有进展吗
Hey, how'd it go at Grand Central?
不错  我找到了这个
Good. I found this.
看标签  这是简·赫茨菲尔德的
Check the tag. It belongs to Jane Herzfeld.
哪儿找到的
Where was it?
就是在邮箱中心简租的那个箱子里
At the mailbox center where Jane bought a box.
她把那儿当成了储物柜存放这个包
She was using it as a locker to hold this bag
还有500块现金
along with $500 in cash.
里面有男人的衣服
Hmm. There's men's clothes,
和一些化妆用品混放在一起
and toiletries mixed up in here.
还有两张她死那天去凤凰城的
And two tickets on the late train to Phoenix
晚班火车票
for the night she died.
她想出城
She was looking to get out of town,
却不是独自离开
but she wasn't going alone.
没有姓名  那要跟她一起走的人是谁呢
No names, so who was going with her?
她的神秘男友
Her mystery man.
她室友说过她在跟某人恋爱
Her roommate said that she was dating someone,
一个还有事要处理的人
someone who had some stuff to work out.
卡沃还一直烦着她  要她背叛李家
And Carver kept hassling her to betray the Lees.
也许他们觉得走为上策
Maybe they figured it was just smarter to get out of town.
但为什么是凤凰城呢
But why Phoenix?
也许是因为那边干燥的气候  这是哮喘吸入器
Maybe a drier climate. It's an asthma inhaler.
但根据验尸报告
But according to the autopsy report,
简没有哮喘
Jane didn't have asthma,
所以这个一定是那个人的
so it must have belonged to the guy.
没有贴处方  但有条形码
no prescription sticker, but there's a bar code.
好  我会打电话给厂商
Yeah, I'm gonna call the manufacturer
让他们查出出处
and have 'em trace it.
我想她的旅伴当时
Oh, and in case her traveling companion
可能在外面等她
was waiting outside for her,
我调出了在邮箱中心的隔壁的
I pulled video from the bank security cameras
银行监控录像
next door to the mailbox center.
好了  停  简出现了
okay, stop. There's Jane.
看看谁跟他在一起
And who's that with her?
芬恩·麦奎恩  简的前男友
Finn McQueen, Jane's ex-boyfriend.
可他跟我们说已经几周没和简说话了
but he told us he hasn't talked to Jane in weeks.
简和芬恩一起出城吗
Jane was leaving town with Finn?
不  那个旅行袋里的衣服  他穿不下
Nah. He's too tall for the clothes in that bag.
-不是他  -对
- It's not him. - Yeah.
他像是在劝她别走
Looks like he's trying to talk her out of going.
他夹克衫里装的是什么
What's that in his jacket?
是把枪
That would be a weapon.
像是把格洛克
Looks like a glock.
鉴证组在你的床垫下发现的
C.S.U. found it under your mattress.
芬恩  这把枪哪里来的
Where'd you get the gun, Finn?
我注意到这些序列号已经被锉掉了
I notice the serial numbers have been filed off.
而这把枪和杀死简的枪支
And that's the same type of weapon
是同一型号
that was used to kill Jane.
那不是我的
That is not mine.
再说你们已确认过我的不在场证明了
And your guy confirmed my alibi.
不在场证明可以作假
Alibis can be bought.
而摄像机不会骗人
Video... doesn't lie.
你知道简要出城
You knew that Jane was leaving town,
你也知道她爱上别人了  不是吗
and you knew she was in love with someone else, didn't you?
-他死不承认  可...  -贝克特
- He keeps saying he didn't do it, but that's... - Beckett.
-他很内疚  -贝克特
- a man with a guilty conscience. - Beckett.
-拿到弹道报告了  -不匹配
- We got word from ballistics. - No match.
那把枪是格洛克17型手枪  可不是我的
The gun's a Glock 17, but it's not mine.
埃斯波西托警探  知道了
Detective Esposito. Gotcha.
我知道凶手是谁了
I know who the killer is.
谢谢你打回电话来
Thanks for getting back to me.
卡塞尔  我们刚得到坏消息
Castle, we just got some bad news,
所以求你别小说式推理
So no hypotheticals.
直接说名字
Just give us a name.
-人家得从头说嘛  -名字
- Well, I have to start at the beginning - Name.
李常金海
Jinhai Li Chang.
好  从头说起
Okay, start from the beginning.
谢谢  我昨晚意识到
Thank you. So I realized last night,
3XK绝不会把警察的枪给朋友
3XK would never give a cop's gun to a friend.
烫手的山芋  谁接谁倒霉
A-a gun that hot would be a curse, not a blessing.
可他会把这把枪给敌人
But he would give it to an enemy.
-所以呢  -所以我查了所有杰瑞·泰森
- So? - So I went over all the incident reports
在新新监狱服刑四年间的事故报告
involving Jerry Tyson during his four years at Sing Sing,
有一份报告相当起眼
and one report in particular stood out.
泰森在器械外场跟一个人起了冲突
Tyson got into it with a guy in the weight yard,
结果他被打断了下巴  进了医院
and he ended up in the infirmary with a broken jaw.
打伤他的人名叫李常金海
The jawbreaker's name-- Jinhai Li Chang.
眼熟吗
Look familiar?
那是菲利普  克利福德·李的长子
That's Philip, Clifford Lee's oldest son.
显然他们家搬到美国的时候
Apparently Papa Clifford anglicized the family's names
老爸给家里人都取了英文名
when they moved into the country,
却从没正式登记注册过
but he never bothered to make them legal.
这也是我花了这么长时间才找到的原因
That's why it took me so long to find it.
菲利普在2008年被控持械
When Philip got his weapons charge in 2008,
收押时他是用中文名登记的
he was booked under his Chinese name.
可如果菲利普和泰森是死敌的话
But if Philip and Tyson were sworn enemies,
菲利普怎么会收那把枪呢
why would Philip accept the gun?
他们俩最终和好了
The two eventually became friends.
不稀奇
It happens.
不可能和杰瑞·泰森和好
Not with Jerry Tyson.
那家伙没朋友  他是个变态
That guy doesn't have any friends. He's a psychopath.
变态报仇  十年不晚
He wanted payback, and he was willing to wait.
泰森把我的枪卖给了菲利普
Tyson sold Philip my gun hoping he'd use it
希望他有朝一日会用
in the future.
然后当菲利普发现简是个线人的时候
And then when Philip found out that Jane was an informant,
他就下手了
he did just that.
实际上  菲利普的动机
Actually, Philip's motive
可能还掺杂了很多私人恩怨
may have been a little more personal than that.
我们在简的旅行袋里发现的那个吸入器的条形码
The bar code on the inhaler that we found in Jane's bag?
那个吸入器是发给常翎麦的
That inhaler was issued to one Ling Mai Chang,
也就是本·李
better known as Ben Lee.
简是要和本出城
Jane was leaving town with Ben.
这么说  这是一段师生恋
So student and tutor become boyfriend and girlfriend.
他们相爱了  现代版"罗密欧与朱丽叶"
They were in love. It's "Romeo And Juliet."
简的确对改过自新的坏男孩情有独钟
Well, Jane did have a thing for reforming bad boys.
对  可一旦加入亚洲黑帮  就是一辈子
Yeah, but Asian gangs-- you're in for life.
没有回头路可走
There's no walking away.
所以就像罗密欧与朱丽叶
So like Romeo and Juliet,
终究还是有人丧生
someone ended up dead.
老哥菲利普发现
Brother Philip found out about their plans
他们准备私奔去凤凰城
to go to Phoenix together,
所以他杀了简  好留住他弟弟
so he murdered Jane to keep little brother in the fold.
这个理论很棒  伙计们
Yeah, it's a great theory, guys.
可我们缺样东西
There's just one thing missing.
证据  目击证人的描述
Evidence, eyewitness accounts--
得有确凿的证据才行
Something to make this case stick.
我知道有个人能帮我们
I know someone that can help us out.
你来放我出去吗
You here to let me out?
芬恩  不是放你出去
Not to let you out, Finn.
是放你自由
To set you free.
你们这帮警察
You cops, man.
你说放我自由  是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean, set me free?
芬恩  说出真相
The truth, Finn.
真相让你自由
The truth sets you free.
我已经找了一整晚
I've been looking for it all night.
终于找到了
I finally found it.
谁能想到真相会藏在1996年的少年犯案底里
Who knew the truth would be hiding in a juvie report from 1996?
你给唐人街一个收注人转钱时被抓了
You got grabbed up moving paper for a Chinatown bookie.
还记得是谁保释你出来的吗
Do you remember who bailed you out?
克利福德·李
Clifford Lee.
你为李家效力多年
You been working for the Lees for years.
都是小差事  因为  芬恩  说白了
Little jobs, because, well, Finn, let's face it,
你就是一衰仔
You're kind of a screwup.
可你不满足于现状
But you wanted more.
所以当你发现本·李需要个家教的时候
So when you found out Ben Lee needed a tutor,
推荐了你的前女友...
you recommended your ex...
简
Jane...
以为这样能给你加点分
Thinking it would earn you points with the family.
然后你眼看着事情脱离了正轨
Then you watched it all go sideways
简和本相爱了
when Jane and Ben fell in love,
他们决定私奔
decided to leave town.
你想
You thought...
如果他们怪罪你怎么办
what if the family blamed you?
因为任何人都不能丢下家族事业
'Cause no one leaves the family business,
即使是为了爱也不行
not even for love.
所以你试图让她回心转意
So you tried to make her change her mind.
你们吵了一架
You fought.
可是她心意已决
But you couldn't change her mind.
所以你打电话给菲利普
So you made a call to Philip,
然后菲利普找上了简
and then Philip went and got Jane.
芬恩  还记得这个吗
Remember this, Finn?
我和她母亲谈过
I talked to her mother.
她说你在她21岁生日那天
She says you gave this cross to Jane
送了她这个十字架
on her 21st birthday.
她死的时候握着这个
She was holding it when she died...
为了寻求慰藉
for comfort.
因为她知道她快死了
Because she knew she was gonna die.
而且她非常...
And she was so...
害怕
afraid.
让我先理清楚
Let me make sure I got this straight.
芬恩·麦奎恩声称他打电话给了我的当事人
Finn McQueen claims that he phoned my client
然后告诉他  他哥本
and told him that his brother Ben
要和简·赫茨菲尔德一起出城
was leaving town with Jane Herzfeld,
据称  我当事人的回答是
to which my client allegedly replied,
"我会处理的"
"I'll take care of it."
你们就只有这些证据吗
Is that all you've got?
我们已经证实菲利普
We've already established that Philip
在女孩被杀的当晚  正与家人待在家中
was at home with his family when the girl was shot.
那为何他的手机信号是从西十二街发出的
Well, then why was his cell phone on West 12th Street?
你的当事人在当晚11点半
Your client made a phone call
打了一通电话到父母家
to his parents' house at 11:30 p.m.
那通电话通过西侧高速公路的一座信号塔转出
That call pinged off a tower off the West Side Highway,
离案发现场只有几个街区
which is a couple of blocks from our murder scene.
你是在打给你父亲
Were you calling your father,
告诉他任务完成了吗
letting him know the job was done?
拜托  警探  就凭他的手机信号
Please, detective. His phone pinged?
你们知道这不足以起诉他谋杀
You know that's not enough to charge him with murder.
暂时还不行  不过给我点时间
Not yet, but give me some time.
如果你的当事人愿意谈谈条件
Listen, if your client wants to talk deal--
做梦吧
Dream on.
我们走  菲利普
Let's go, Philip.
你用我的配枪杀了那个女孩
You killed that girl, and you used my weapon to do it,
让我现在备受煎熬
and now I carry that weight.
我告诉你  在你尝到同样的滋味之前
Trust me when I say to you that I will not rest
我绝不善罢甘休  相信我
until I make you carry it, too.
盘问结束了
We're done here.
如果你们不事先告知我的事务所就试图
And if you attempt to contact my client or his family again
与我的当事人及其家人联系
without first notifying my office,
我们会起诉警局骚扰
we'll sue the department for harassment.
好了  行了
All right. Okay.
我们明白
We got it.
这是你们第二次无凭无据去找李一家
This is the second time you've gone at the Lees with nothing.
现在菲利普·李请了律师
Now Philip Lee has lawyered up,
他很可能已经把枪脱手了
he's probably gotten rid of the gun,
加上四名家庭成员  和众多佣人
and he has four family members and various household help
愿意为他提供案发当时的不在场证明
willing to alibi him for the time of the murder.
手机信号显示他当时就在
The cell phone puts him in the vicinity
-案发现场附近  -附近
- of the murder scene. - Vicinity?
芬恩·麦奎恩说过
Finn McQueen said--
芬恩·麦奎恩无法证实究竟发生了什么  卡塞尔
Finn McQueen cannot testify to what happened, Castle.
他不在现场
He wasn't there.
要有证据
Make your case.
但搜集证据
But you do it now,
不能骚扰李一家
without harassing the Lee family.
长官  我们需要对他们施压
Sir, we need to keep leaning on them.
我们要趁热打铁
We need to keep the heat on.
不行  你们得另想办法  这是命令
No. You need to stay away, and that's an order.
难道要我们写下杀死简的凶手的名字
So what, we just write the name of Jane's killer
就这么放他走吗
in a file and we let him walk free?
我们是警察  不是文书
That makes us clerks, not cops.
回家休息  莱恩
Take the rest of the day off, Ryan.
你需要清醒清醒
You need to clear your head.
这还没完  伙计
It's not over yet, bro.
我们只是需要找到证人
We just need someone to go on record,
知道当晚究竟发生了什么的人
someone who knows what happened that night.
是啊  唯一清楚此事的人就是菲利普·李
Yeah. The only one who really knows is Philip Lee.
你去哪
Where you going?
遵照警监说的
I'm gonna do just like the captain said,
给自己放天假
take the rest of the day off.
无论你去哪  我跟你一起去
Wherever you're going, I'm going with you.
这是我的执拗
It's my fight.
你不想让我卷进来
And you don't want me getting involved.
可这也是我的案子
It's my case, too.
你是我的搭档
And you're my partner.
我要去问问本·李
I'm taking a run at Ben Lee.
李家一定会把他关起来
The Lees will have him locked down.
我打赌他老爹一定不会让他单独跑出来
I'm betting his old man won't let him go out in public alone.
那么
Then...
我想一身警察装扮是进不去的
I guess we can't go in there looking like cops.
真巧
Oh, snap.
是菲利普吗  忙什么呢  小子
Is that Philip? Yo, what's good, son?
哥们  我有阵子没见你了
Man, I ain't seen you in a minute.
哥们  最近在哪儿混
Man, how you been?
他以为我是我哥  鬼佬总是分不清
He thinks I'm my brother. Happens with the Gweilo.
-怎么了  -走开
- What's up? - Move along.
喂  你干嘛碰我
Hey, man, why you touching up on me?
喂  你最好注意你的语气
Hey, man, you better check your totem.
菲利普  告诉他我们是哥们
Hey, Philip, tell him that we boys.
告诉你的保镖
Tell your boy thor
-我们是好哥们  -行了  跟我出去
- that we boys. - Yeah, let's go outside.
你等会可以打菲利普手机
You can call Philip on his cell later.
菲利普  快跟他说
Philip, tell him!
伙计  你变了  菲利普
Man, you've changed, Philip.
本  你好
Hey, Ben.
你不该来这儿
You shouldn't be here.
我只想聊聊
I just want to talk.
聊什么
About what?
简的事
About Jane.
简死了
Jane is dead.
怎么  你们之间的一切也都死了吗
So you let it all just die with her?
发生了什么
What happened, huh?
上大学也许让你觉得
College maybe got you thinking
出去闯闯会比
that there's something better out there
当个低劣毒贩子强得多
than being just a low-life drug dealer?
简真的让你动了心
Jane made you really want to try?
你还是可以逃出去
You can still get out.
我保证  你会很安全
And I promise, you'll be safe.
你们警察的保证都是胡言
You cops and your promises, man.
卡沃向简保证她会没事
Carver promised Jane she'd be safe.
可结果呢
Look what happened.
这事关我的家庭
You're talking about my family.
这事关你今后的人生
I'm talking about your life.
简为了你的抗争而死
Jane died fighting your battle.
我知道你可以用更好的方式纪念她
I know you can honor her better than this.
本  你没事吧
Ben, you okay?
你知道怎么找我
You know how to find me.
你们俩究竟是怎么想的
What the hell were you two thinking,
在盖茨明说了要"另想办法"之后
going to see Ben Lee when Gates specifically
去见本·李
said "Stay away"?
谁会让她知道呢  贝克特  反正不是我
Who's gonna tell her, Beckett? Not me.
莱恩  你打算向警监打小报告吗
Ryan, are you planning on telling the Captain what we did?
我不会  卡塞尔呢
Not me. Castle?
我吗  绝不
Who me? No way.
算你狠  臭屁小子
Nice, smart-ass.
那要是本·李告诉了他爸爸
And what about when Ben Lee tells his daddy
他们的律师又打电话给盖茨呢
and Gates gets a phone call from their lawyer?
你俩会被停职的
You two are gonna get benched.
本·李不会告诉他父亲的
Ben Lee's not gonna tell his father.
-你怎么知道  -因为
- How do you know? - Because...
我看着他的眼睛  我看到了他承受的痛苦
I looked him in the eye and I saw the pain he's in.
也许他不够有勇气站出来
Maybe he's not man enough to stand up for himself,
但是他也不会出卖我
but he's not gonna rat me out, either.
你们真是太冒险了
You guys took a hell of a chance.
贝克特  你的语气像个头儿了
Beckett, you're starting to sound like a boss.
下次不要擅自行动  我也好...
Just let me know next time so I can help--
莱恩警探
Detective Ryan.
有人找你
There's someone here to see you.
爸爸说你在楼下
Papa said you were down here.
你现在上大四了  不必这么用功
Ah, you're a senior now. You don't need to work this hard.
我周一有考试
I have a test on Monday.
别管它了  我们出去逛逛
Blow it off. We'll go out.
我不想去
I don't want to go.
菲利普
Philip.
如果不是他们发现了简的尸体
If they hadn't found Jane,
如果她还被掩埋着
if she'd stayed hidden...
我就永远不会知道她已经死了
I never would've known what happened to her.
你真的想让我就那样被蒙在鼓里吗
Would you really have let me wonder for the rest of my life?
有时候不知道真相  反而更好
Sometimes it's a gift, not knowing the truth.
所以说如果她只是失踪  我就会相信
So if she were just missing, I could believe that
她还在别处好好活着吗
she were alive somewhere?
我就可以假装...
I could pretend...
像小孩那样
Like a child?
可她不是失踪了
But she's not missing!
情况不妙
I don't like this.
本应该诱导菲利普招供
Ben is supposed to lead Philip to a confession,
而不是逼迫他认罪
not forces him to confession.
给他点时间
You guys, just give him a minute.
她死了
She's dead,
我不再是个孩子了
and I'm not a child.
时间久了
In time,
你就会知道  这是为你好
you'll see, it was for the best.
菲利普在闪烁其辞
Philip's dancing around it.
听着  一旦他认罪
Look, the second he acknowledges guilt,
我们就冲进去
we're moving in.
快点  快点
Come on. Come on.
她哭了吗  她有问起我吗
Did she cry? Did she ask for me?
本
Ben.
别这样
Don't do this.
我要知道
I need to know.
你脑子现在不清楚
You're not thinking clearly.
我们明天再谈
We'll talk about this tomorrow.
如果你不把真相告诉我
If you don't tell me everything,
我们再也不是兄弟了
we can no longer be brothers.
你戴着窃听器吗
You wearing a wire?
莱恩  他起疑心了
Ryan, he's tipping.
或许本可以扭转局面
Maybe Ben can turn it around.
不行  我们得赶快把他救出来
No, we have to pull him out now.
再等等
Just...
窃听器  什么意思
Wire. What is this?
让我看看
Let me see.
把衣服敞开我瞧瞧
Open your shirt.
-我不需要向你证明什么  -本
- I don't need to prove anything to you. - Ben!
我的好弟弟  这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance, little brother.
把衣服敞开
Show me.
行动  快点
Let's go. Let's move.
你要像杀死简一样
You gonna shoot me now,
杀死我吗
like you did to Jane?
别逼我
Don't push me.
去死
Go to hell.
把手举起来
Get 'em up!
趴下
Down!
叛徒  叛徒
Traitor! Traitor.
你毁了我的人生
You ruined my life!
不要  本
No, Ben!
不  不
No, no!
本  把枪放下
Ben, put down the gun!
不  别开枪
No! Don't!
不  本
No, Ben!
不
No!
把他拖出去
Get him outta here!
本  上帝  本
Ben! Oh, god, Ben! Ben!
快叫救护车  快点
Call it in. Rush the bus.
救护车已经在路上了
They're on the way.
本
Ben!
对不起
I'm so sorry.
该死  对不起
Damn it. I am so sorry.
上帝啊  真的很抱歉
Oh, god. I'm so sorry.
录音带上的内容已足以使陪审团
There's enough on a tape to sway a jury
排除一切合理怀疑
from reasonable doubt.
我们在你车子里找到的可卡因与
And the coke that we found in your car
在简尸体上发现的残留物是吻合的
is a match for the residue found on Jane's body.
而且
And then...
还有这把枪
There's this.
这把你刚指着你弟弟的枪
The gun that you pointed at your brother.
莱恩警探已经认出
Detective Ryan positively identified it
是他被偷的警枪
as his stolen service weapon.
同时它也是
It is also the same gun
杀死简·赫茨菲尔德的凶枪
that was used to kill Jane Herzfeld.
你将被控一级谋杀
You're looking at murder one,
终生不得假释
life with no parole.
我的当事人有些你们可能会感兴趣的信息
My client has some information that might interest the NYPD.
什么信息
What kind of information?
杰瑞·泰森
Jerry Tyson.
3XK
3XK.
你知道些什么
What about him?
他给我枪的时候  我们有谈过
When he gave me the gun, we talked.
我知道他会往哪逃
I know where he was headed,
他会用什么假名
and what name he's gonna use.
李想以15到20年有期徒刑
So Lee wants 15 to 25
十年后准许假释
with parole in ten
作为交换泰森新化名的条件
for giving us Tyson's new alias.
我会跟副地检官建议此认罪协议
I need to give the A.D.A. a recommendation.
卡塞尔  这也许就是我们抓住3XK的机会
This might be our chance to get 3XK, Castle.
不是
No.
这是他下的套
It's a setup.
杰瑞·泰森把枪交给菲利普·李时
Jerry Tyson gave that gun to Philip Lee
就知道他肯定会用这把枪
knowing he would use it,
很有可能  他也知道
so there's a good chance he knew
最终我们会抓到菲利普
we'd eventually get to Philip.
也许吧  那又怎样
Maybe. So what?
所以泰森对菲利普说的一切都是假的
So nothing Tyson told Philip would be the truth.
如果菲利普·李
Giving Philip Lee
能用假信息换取一份满意的认罪协议
a good deal for bad information,
那样杰瑞·泰森就又赢了我们一次
that's just another win for Jerry Tyson.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我肯定
Sure enough.
简·赫茨菲尔德理应得到公正
Jane Herzfeld deserves justice.
菲利普·李终身监禁
Life in prison for Philip Lee.
没得谈
No deals.
我们会抓到3XK的
We'll get 3XK.
通过自己的调查
And we'll do it right.
不错嘛  卡塞尔
Damn, Castle.
看看你  已经像个真警察了
Look at you, thinking like a real cop.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
你应该高兴的
Hey. You could look a little happier.
今天不是抓到凶手了吗
Today was a win, right?
我一直在想赛斯·卡沃
Well, I keep thinking about Seth Carver,
把简独自一人送进李家
sending Jane into the Lees', all alone,
根本没有后援
with no backup.
我真的算个好警察吗
Do I really get to call myself a better cop?
你绝对是个好警察  凯文
You are a better cop, Kevin.
你是个好人
You're a better man,
因为你没让本独自面对危险
because you didn't send him in there alone.
看吧  你的好小伙来了
Hey, there's your boy.
本  看见你没事就好了
Ben... Good to see you back on your feet.
之前的表演真令人印象深刻啊
Hey, that was a pretty impressive performance back there.
你可以去做特技演员了
Yes, you have a future in stunt work, my friend.
这是麦克·杜恩执法官
Guys, this is Marshal Mike Drooen
保护证人组的
from Witness Protection.
他会护送本去洛杉矶的新家
He's escorting Ben to his new home in Los Angeles.
警探们  本  你的飞机将于一小时后起飞
Detectives. Ben, your plane leaves in an hour.
多谢  给我一点时间
Thanks. I just need a minute.
谢谢你
Thank you.
如果不是你  我根本没有勇气那样做
I wouldn't have had the courage to do what I did without you.
现在你可以过自己想要的生活了
Well, you have your life back now.
按你自己的方式生活
Live it on your own terms.
这才是她希望看到的
It's what she wanted.
我们小声庆祝下  好吗
Let's, uh, keep this party a little quiet, though, all right?
如果警监听见了  骂的肯定是我
If the Captain hears, I'm sure she'll blame me.
谁会去告密吗
Who's gonna tell her?
我肯定不会  你会吗
Not me. You?
我也不会
Nope.
你会吗  莱恩
What about you, Ryan?
那就没问题了
Well, then I think we're good.
那么  敬我的搭档
Well, then... To my partner
凯文·莱恩
Kevin Ryan
出类拔萃的警探
a credit to the job.
敬莱恩
To Ryan.
我想说句祝酒词
I'd like to make a toast.
为无畏的勇气
To bravery
为至死不渝的承诺
and commitment,
为爱和义无反顾的牺牲
to love and sacrifice.
敬简
To Jane.